By using our site you agree with our [cookie policy](https://www.moneydashboard.com/privacy#contents17)

Ok, got it

Log in

󰅖

We recently launched Money Dashboard Neon. If you're looking for the existing app (Money Dashboard Classic) you can log in below.

[Neon

Money Dashboard

󰁔](http://app.moneydashboard.com/login)[Classic

Money Dashboard

󰁔](http://my.moneydashboard.com/)

󰘥

Need help? [Click here](https://support.moneydashboard.com/hc/en-us/articles/360044755832-Why-did-Money-Dashboard-develop-a-new-application-)

Privacy Policy
==============

**Important information and who we are**

This is the Privacy Policy for “Money Dashboard”. Money Dashboard is an Account Information Service Provider (AISP). Our service is provided at [**www.moneydashboard.com**](https://www.moneydashboard.com/) and associated mobile applications. It allows you to see all your online banking accounts in one place, and analyses your account information and transactions to help you spend, save and borrow more efficiently (which we refer to in this policy as our “service” or “services”).

Money Dashboard is owned and operated by Money Dashboard Limited. Our company number is SC301187. Our registered office is at Suite 2, Ground Floor, Orchard Brae House, 30 Queensferry Road, Edinburgh, EH4 2HS.

When we refer to our trading name “Money Dashboard” or “we”, “us” or “our” in this policy, we are referring to the Money Dashboard Limited. We are the data ‘controller’ in relation to the personal data you provide to us, which means we determine the purposes and the way in which your personal data is, or will be, processed.

**Purpose of this privacy policy**

This policy aims to give you information on how we collect and process any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us. We want you to be confident when you use our service that you know what your personal data is being used for, and that it is being kept safe.

It is important that you read this privacy policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you, so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy policy supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

**How to contact us**

If there is anything you don’t understand or you’re not happy about, please get in touch with us by:

* Emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.moneydashboard.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**If you have any concerns**

You will always have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory body. The relevant authority in the UK is the [**Information Commissioner's Office**](https://https//ico.org.uk/). However, if you do have a complaint, we would appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns first, so please do contact us in the first instance.

**How is your personal data collected?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

* Direct interactions. You may give us your personal data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us in person, by email, by phone, by post or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when registering to use our service.
* Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. Please see below on Cookies for further information.
* Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources, for example, analytics providers such as Google.

**Information Which We May Collect**

We may collect and process the following information about you:

* Registration Information: To register to use our service you will have to supply us with your email address, UK postcode and date of birth. Registration information also includes the credentials you share with us to allow us to access your Account Information.
* Additional Personal Information: You may choose to submit additional personal information when you register for the service, for example your name, your preferred pronoun (he, she, they).
* Unique user reference: This is a reference which we assign to you when you sign up to use our service, to create your own unique data record.
* Account and Transactional Information: When you ‘Add Accounts’ to our service, we may access, store and process your Account Information held by your account provider. Account Information includes, for example, your account details, account transaction information, account features and benefits and regular payments.
* Custom Tags: We will collect and save any custom tags that you may choose to create in order to describe your transactions within your dashboard.
* Technical Information: When you browse our website, we automatically collect some technical information about your visit to our website, including, but not limited to, information about the device you are using to access Money Dashboard (for example, mobile device or web), the IP address used to connect your computer to the internet, your browser type and version and your browser plug-in types and version.
* Customer Testimonials: This could include your name, social media handle and/or any testimonial, review or other comment on our products or services that you choose to provide to us.
* Financial Services Records: This is record-keeping information which we collect in order to meet our regulatory and statutory duties.

**How we use your information**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

* Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you (i.e. when you sign up to our service).
* Where we have your prior consent to use your personal data (for example, where you have consented to receiving marketing).
* Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.
* Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Please note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

‍

| Purpose / activity | Our lawful basis for processing this data | Type(s) of Data we use for this purpose |
| --- | --- | --- |
| To register you as a customer to use our service | Performance of a Contract with you (i.e. Contract) | Registration Information |
| To manage our relationship with you (including notifying you about changes to our terms and conditions or this privacy policy) | Contract; Legal obligation | Email address |
| To understand our user base better | Legitimate interests (to understand our user demographic and what users want to get out of our service) | Registration Information, Additional Personal Information |
| Requesting your participation in online surveys | Consent | Email address |
| Posting customer testimonials and reviews on our website | Consent | Customer Testimonials (we contact you to ask if you are happy for us to include your testimonial, and how you would like your name and/or social media handles to appear) |
| To tell you about goods or services (marketing material) that we feel may be of interest to you | Consent | Email address |
| To create your personal data record, which we need to uniquely identify you | Contract | Unique User Reference |
| To create your dashboard | Contract | Account and Transactional information, Custom Tags (if you have created these) |
| To provide user support and technical instructions regarding your account | Contract | Registration information, Unique User Reference, Account and Transactional information and Technical information |
| To monitor and improve our service | Legitimate interests (to track the use of our service and identify areas where we can improve service performance or service functionality. This includes business and technical improvements) | Registration information, Technical information, Additional Personal Information |
| To create aggregated market research, from which all personal data is removed. | Legitimate interests (We sell this anonymised market research to clients to create the revenue we need to run our business and to provide you with a free service) | Account and Transactional information, Registration information |
| Use of necessary, functional and analytical cookies (see Cookies section for further information on specific purposes) | Legitimate interests (in operating our website); Consent | Technical information |
| To maintain our statutory records to comply with our FCA requirements | Legal obligation | Financial Services Records |

You may control your subscriptions to any of the above marketing content notifications via the Settings feature of our service.

**The information we may give to or share with somebody else**

We may share your personal information in the following ways:

* to companies that provide services to help us operate the application and communicate with users. These companies are authorised to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us, and via contractual agreements that establish their responsibilities to protect your data;
* to HMRC, regulators and other authorities or bodies who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, or investigate fraud;
* to professional advisers, including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
* if Money Dashboard is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information;
* to any other third party with your prior agreement to do so, where such agreement will be recorded by us, and retained in line with our data retention policy, and include the purpose, frequency and duration of the information sharing;

**International transfers**

Some of our external third parties are based outside the UK so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside of the UK.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the UK, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

* We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data.
* Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved for use in the UK which give personal data the same protection it has in the UK. For further details.
* In any other case, we will obtain your explicit consent before any transfer takes place.

**Your rights**

Under certain circumstances, you have the following rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data:

* Access to your information
* Request correction of your personal data
* Request deletion of your personal data
* Object to processing of your personal data
* Request restriction of processing your personal data
* Request transfer of your personal data
* Right to withdraw consent
* Right to review by an independent authority

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.moneydashboard.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

We will respond to all legitimate requests within 30 days. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

**Access to your information**

You have the right to ask for a copy of the information which we hold on you (commonly known as a ‘data subject access request’). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Correcting personal data**

You have the right to request that we correct personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate information we hold corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data that you provide to us.

**Deleting personal data**

You may ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. This is more commonly known as the ‘right to be forgotten’. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law.

Please note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request to delete or remove personal data for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Objecting to processing**

You have the right to stop us processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. We will always inform you if we intend to use your personal data for such purposes, or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can usually exercise your right to prevent such marketing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.moneydashboard.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

You may also object to us processing your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Restriction of processing**

This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:

* if you want us to establish the data's accuracy;
* where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it;
* where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or
* you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Transferring your personal data**

In certain circumstances, you may request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format.

Please note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdrawing consent**

Where we are relying on consent to process your personal data you can withdraw your consent at any time. Please note that this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent.

**How long we keep your data**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

We will normally retain your information for a period of 30 days after your account is deactivated or 30 days after your information is no longer needed to provide you with our services. After this period, the data will be deleted from our systems and we will be unable to access it. In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data sooner: see Deleting personal data above for further information. If you do wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.moneydashboard.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

As an FCA regulated firm, we have statutory obligations to retain records with respect to the financial services we have provided to you, or introduced to you. Such records will be retained for the shorter of either 12 months beyond the conclusion of the financial service provided, or 5 years. If you cancel your account with us, these statutory records will be archived, and all other information will be deleted.

Where we anonymise your personal data (i.e. so that it can no longer be associated with you) for further research or statistical purposes, then we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**Security**

Please see our full security policy at [**https://www.moneydashboard.com/security/**](https://www.moneydashboard.com/security/)

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Links to Other Websites**

Our website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. This includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, the “Share this" button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. Clicking on those links or enabling those Features may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. For example, these Features may collect your IP address or which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. We do not control these third-party websites or Features and are not responsible for their privacy statements. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. When you leave one of our websites, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may need to modify this privacy policy from time to time, to reflect any key changes in our service or as required by our regulators.

This version was last updated on 13th September 2021.

**Changes to your details**

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. To access and change your personal information, you should log in to your online account on our website and make the necessary changes. The changes will be effective as soon as you save them to your Profile, and a confirmation message will be displayed.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

What are cookies?

A cookie is a text file containing a small amount of information that is sent to your browser when you visit a website. The cookie is then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises it. Cookies are an extremely useful technology and do lots of different jobs.

We may collect information through the use of cookies.

**What cookies do we use?**

We have listed below all the cookies that we use. These fall into the following categories:

* **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website.
* **Analytics/performance cookies**. These types of cookies allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users can easily find what they are looking for.
* **Functionality cookies**. These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences.
* **Targeting cookies**. These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below:

| Cookie | Type | Purpose | More information |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| AWSALB | Necessary | Used by Amazon Web Services (AWS) to provide Load Balancing functionality | The AWS Load balancer distributes all the users across the servers that make up our infrastructure. When you first visit our website you will be allocated to one of those servers – this cookie remembers which server so all page requests are from the same server. |
| \_ga\*, \_gid\* | Analytics | Used by Google analytics to track page views and site performance | [https://tinyurl.com/q3wz83z](https://tinyurl.com/q3wz83z) |
| Access\_token, extole\_access\_token, xtl\_bid | Analytics | Used by Extole to credit people who refer friends |     |
| \_zlcmid | Functionality | Used by Zendesk to support customer service enquiries |     |
| \_dd\_s | Functionality | Used by Datadog to monitor the performance of the application. |     |
| Mdbmpt | Functionality | Used by Money Dashboard to remember your email, if you select that option on login |     |
| \_\_RequestVerificationToken | Necessary | Used by the application to ensure secure login | When a form (such as the login form) is submitted to our application, we have to make sure that it has been submitted from the correct place (i.e. our application). This cookie ensures this and protects against “fake” form submissions and login attempts. |
| JSESSIONID | Necessary | Used by the application to remember your current logged in “session”. | Everytime you load a page on the application, we have to check that you are logged in correctly. This is called the “session” – the period between logging in and logging out. This cookie remembers if you are logged in and allows us to only present data / pages to you that are private. |
| mdb-authentication | Necessary | Used by Money Dashboard to ensure you are logged in. |     |
| Fr  | Analytics | Used by Facebook to track analytics |     |
| hasUser | Functionality | Used to track if the current visitor is a subscribed user |     |

**Important information about cookies**

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

**How do I change my cookie settings?**

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set, visit [**www.aboutcookies.org**](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [**www.allaboutcookies.org**](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To find out how to manage cookies on popular browsers:

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit [**http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout**](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Last updated: May 2022

Authorised and regulated by the [Financial Conduct Authority](https://register.fca.org.uk/ShPo_FirmDetailsPage?id=0010X000047U3U5QAK) (reg. 800652) & registered provider on [openbanking.org.uk](https://www.openbanking.org.uk/regulated-providers/the-one-place-capital/)

Copyright © 2021 Money Dashboard Ltd. All rights reserved. "Money Dashboard" is a trademark. Money Dashboard Ltd is a registered AIS (Account Information Service) provider, reference no. 800652 at [fca.org.uk/register](http://fca.org.uk/register).
